(
"ai_sub_version": "1.11.0",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 3,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
百鬼あやめ 7周年記念ライブ ～天女繚華～
Nakiri Ayame 7th Anniversary Live ~Tennyo Ryouka~
百鬼あやめ
Nakiri Ayame
兎田ぺこら / Azki
Usada Pekora / Azki
大神ミオ / 白上フブキ
Ookami Mio / Shirakami Fubuki
さくらみこ / 雪花ラミィ
Sakura Miko / Yukihana Lamy
フワワ・アビスガード / モココ・アビスガード
Fuwawa Abyssgard / Mococo Abyssgard
天音かなた / 宝鐘マリン
Amane Kanata / Houshou Marine
百鬼あやめ 7周年記念ライブ ～天女繚華～
Nakiri Ayame 7th Anniversary Live ~Tennyo Ryouka~
ゆらゆらり　はらはらり
Swaying gently, falling softly
色とりどり　乱れ咲き
In a riot of various colors
花の街　思い出す
I remember the town of flowers
この空から
From this sky
百花繚乱
Hyakka Ryouran
どんな出来事から
From whatever events
やってきたこの場所は
This place I've come to
遥か遠くにあった
It was far, far away
煌びやかな舞台
This dazzling stage
ハッとするほど鮮やかな
A world so vivid it takes your breath away
世界があるんだと知った
I learned that it exists
あなたの無理難題に
To your unreasonable demands
応えていくその度に
Every time I respond
アッと言わせるような
Something that leaves you speechless
奇想天外な答え合わせで
With an unexpected answer check
辿り着いたその先に
At the end of that journey
新しい景色が待っているんだ
A new view is waiting
摩訶不思議なミステリー
A mysterious mystery
次から次に起こるたび
Every time they happen one after another
巧妙なからくりも
Even the ingenious tricks
暴いてみせましょう
Let me expose them
どんな難題でも
No matter how difficult the problem
種や仕掛けはあるんだ
There are always tricks and gimmicks
副作用は気にしない
I don't care about the side effects
必ずや導き出すから
Because I will surely lead the way
あぁ この場所で触れた
Ah, the human sorrows and joys
人の哀しみや喜びがある
I've touched in this place...
そのひとつひとつが
Each and every one of them
心を震わせる
Makes my heart tremble.
ハッとしちゃうほど
To the point that it takes my breath away,
鮮やかな世界がここにあるんだ
A vivid world is right here.
あなたの無理難題に応えていく毎日に
In my days of responding to your unreasonable demands,
アッと言わせるような奇想天外な答え合わせ
A checking of answers so fantastic it leaves people speechless.
たどり着いたその先に
Beyond that point I've reached,
新しい私が待っているんだ
A new me is waiting.
あの頃は想像もしていない
A future that I couldn't have imagined back then
未来が咲き始めている
Has begun to bloom.
こんな日々も悪くはないかな
Maybe these kinds of days aren't so bad.
ゆらゆらり ひらひらり
Swaying, fluttering,
離れては寄り添って
Drifting apart then drawing close.
そよぐ風に身を任せ
Leaving myself to the gentle breeze,
幽夜に舞う
Dancing in the dark night.
はーい！ということで、今日は皆さん来てくれてありがとう！
Hi! So, thank you all for coming today!
みんな見てる？見てますか？
Is everyone watching? Are you watching?
ということで見て！今日はこの新衣装なんですよ！
Anyway, look! I'm in this new outfit today!
みんな気づいた？よね？気づいたよね？流石に。
Did everyone notice? Right? You noticed, right? Obviously.
はーい！ということで見てください。
Yes! So please, take a look.
この煌びやかな和風の新衣装でーす！やったー！
It's this brilliant Japanese-style new outfit! Yay!
ということでですね、これは今回、天女衣装となっております。
So, this time, it's called the "Tennyo Costume."
傘も合わせて見てください。傘、ちょっと見えるかな？
Please check out the matching umbrella too. I wonder if you can see it?
これ見て！余のね、ちょっと衣装と同じ柄で、今回新しく作っていただきました！
Look at this! It has the same pattern as my outfit, and they made it specifically for me!
イェーイ！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you very much!
はい！ということで、この傘以外にもですね、ちょっとこの後新しいアイテムもちょっと出てくるので、そちらは要チェックです。
Yes! So, besides this umbrella, some new items will appear later, so keep an eye out for those.
と、いうわけで、えー、1曲目は「百花繚乱」を歌って踊らせていただきました！
Anyway, for the first song, I performed "Hyakka Ryouran"!
まだね、ちょっと花の蕾を使って、ちょっと新衣装にチェンジさせていただいたんですけど、どうでした？
I used flower buds to change into this new outfit, but how was it?
どうだった？どうだった？
How was it? How was it?
おー、ありがとうございます、ありがとうございます！可愛いですよね、はい！
Oh, thank you, thank you! It's cute, isn't it? Yes!
ということで、今回のライブタイトルが「天女繚華」ということで、
So, the title of today's live is "Tennyo Ryouka."
ちょっとこの新衣装チェンジとか、これからのゲストの登場とかでちょっとね、
With the new outfit change and the guests appearing later,
お花を多く使っているので、花が咲き乱れるという意味を込めて、今回この「天女繚華」というライブ名にさせていただきました！
we're using a lot of flowers, so I chose "Tennyo Ryouka" to mean flowers blooming profusely!
見て、ちょっと、ちょっとね、後ろにもチラッとお花が見えたり、
Look, you can see flowers peeking out in the back too,
余の衣装にもちょっとお花があったり、なんだりしているんですけれども。
and there are flowers here and there on my outfit as well.
はい！ということで、この衣装に合わせて、今回もステージ新しく作っていただきました！やったー！
Yes! And to match this outfit, they made a brand new stage for us! Yay!
え、めっちゃ綺麗じゃない？見て！
Isn't it super beautiful? Look!
この桜と、このでっかい月！
These cherry blossoms, and this giant moon!
このでっかい月とね、この両端に、こっちにもありますけど桜。
This giant moon, and the cherry blossoms on both ends here.
いや、めちゃめちゃ綺麗でしょ？すごいでしょ, これ！
It's really, really beautiful, right? It's amazing!
もう、めちゃめちゃ考えました！もう、めちゃくちゃね、ちょっと運営さんたちと一緒にお話し合いをしたりとかして実現していただきました。
I thought about it so much! I talked it over a lot with the staff to make this happen.
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ということで、この床にもね、ちょっと。
And on the floor, too...
分かります？気づきました？
Can you see? Did you notice?
ちょっとね、お花もこの散りばめられていたり、余の足元にもね、
There are flowers scattered around, and at my feet too,
この梅なのかな？このお花を、こうライトみたいな感じで照らしていただいたり。
these might be plum blossoms? These flowers are being projected like lights.
これちょっとね、細かくめちゃ作ってもらってます！ありがとうございます！
They really put a lot of detail into this! Thank you!
なんで、それも含めてちょっとめちゃめちゃ見ていただきたいなと思っております。
So, I'd really like you to take a close look at all of that.
まあ、このね、まあ、ちょっと、まあ、気になってますよね？この衣装。
Now then, you're curious about this outfit, right?
ちょっとみんなで近くで見てもらおうかな？じゃあ、ちょっと上からいいですか、カメラさん？
Let's let everyone see it up close. Camera person, can we get a shot from above?
あ、ありがとうございます！あ、このね。
Ah, thank you! So, this...
気づきました？この、もう髪型からちょっといつもと違うんですよ。
Did you notice? Even my hairstyle is different from usual.
ちょっとお団子。まあ、いつものちょっと3D衣装の雰囲気も残しつつ、
These buns. Well, while keeping the vibe of my usual 3D outfit,
残しつつね、ちょっと新しい髪型にさせていただきました！
while keeping that, I had them give me a new hairstyle!
そしてそして、じゃあちょっといいですか？あ、あら、あら可愛いですよね！
And also, and also, can we see here? Ah, oh, it's cute, isn't it?
あららららら、このお花。ステージの各所にも入って...
Oh my, these flowers. They're also included in various parts of the stage...
このね、梅っぽい花っぽい感じも入れていただきつつ...
With these plum and flower-like patterns included...
見て！見てください！
Look! Please take a look!
あ、この振袖にもちゃんとついてます。
Ah, they're properly attached to these long sleeves too.
このお花。
These flowers.
きれいでしょ？見て。きれいでしょ？
Pretty, right? Look. Pretty, right?
可愛よでしょ？いいでしょ？
Cute, right? Great, right?
はい。ということで、この足元にもちょっと注目していただきたいんですけど。
Right. So, I'd also like you to pay attention to my feet.
見て！この草履も新しくなりました！
Look! These zori sandals are new too!
可愛いよね、かっこいいよね、ちょっと。
They're cute and kind of cool.
袖の色と合わせて、こっちはね、白で。
Matching the sleeve colors, this one is white...
こっちはちょっと茶色っぽい感じになってます。
...and this one is a bit brownish.
そしてね、この衣装すごいところが、
And the amazing thing about this outfit is...
どんだけ踊ってもですよ。足元見てください。
...no matter how much I dance. Look at my feet.
めっちゃ伸びるんです、これ！すごいでしょ！
They stretch so much! Amazing, right!
これ！すごくないこれ？
Look! Isn't this incredible?
どんだけやってもめっちゃ伸びるからね！
No matter what I do, they stretch a lot!
ということで、はい、小ネタでした。
So, yeah, that was a little fun fact.
はい。じゃあちょっと、ま、この新しい衣装にもなりましたし、
Okay. Well, since I have this new outfit...
新しいステージにもなったということで。
...and a brand-new stage...
じゃあちょっと、ちょっと1枚でもね、ちょっとお写真撮りますか？お写真。
...shall we take a photo? Just one photo.
せっかくやし、この桜のさんめっちゃ咲いてるところあるから、
Since we're here, there's a spot where the cherry blossoms are in full bloom.
ここでちょっと撮ろうよ。撮ろうよ。
Let's take it here. Let's do it.
じゃあちょっとカメラさん来てください。こっちこっちこっち。
Mr. Camera, please come over here. This way, this way.
あ、めっちゃ、めっちゃ映える！見て！
Ah, it's so photogenic! Look!
すごいでしょこれ！めっちゃきれいだよね。
Isn't this amazing? It's so beautiful.
このね、桜の色とかもめっちゃ決めました。めっちゃ。
I was very particular about the color of these cherry blossoms.
も、でもね、このライブ中にもめちゃめちゃ変わったりするの、
And, you know, it changes throughout the live performance...
ライティングとかもね、変わったり雰囲気もまた変わるので、
...the lighting and the atmosphere will shift too.
それも含めて見てほしいんですけど。ま、ちょっとそれを込めて、ちょっとここでお写真なんか撮っちゃおうかな！
I want you to see all of that. So, with that in mind, let's take some photos here!
みんな、みんなスクショいっぱい撮ってくださいね。
Everyone, please take lots of screenshots.
みんなハッシュタグつけて、たくさんポストしてね！
Use the hashtag and post them plenty!
撮れてる？撮れてる？いい感じ？いい感じか？
Are you getting them? Are they looking good? Is it good?
じゃあ、ちょっと、傘なしバージョンもちょっとやってみますか？
Well, shall we try a version without the umbrella?
どう？傘なし。傘なしもちょっと撮れるかしら？
How's this? No umbrella. I wonder if you can catch this too?
お、いいんじゃない？いいんじゃない？あ、撮れてる？
Oh, isn't this good? Isn't it? Ah, are you getting it?
お、撮れてますか？お、めっちゃいい！
Oh, are you getting them? Oh, that's great!
めっちゃいい角度じゃん！う、いいね、いいね、いいね！
That's a perfect angle! Nice, nice, nice!
へへ。
Hehe.
はい。じゃあということで、ま、ちょっとお写真はね、これぐらいにさせていただきまして。
Okay then. Let's wrap up the photo session here.
続きはね、ちょっと細かい衣装やら、ま、ちょっとスクショタイムはね、メインの方でちょっと用意しようかなと思ってるんで。
For more costume details and more screenshot time, I'm planning to set that up in the main part.
な、そのあともね、ミニライブとかもありますので、
After that, we'll have a mini-live performance as well.
そちらもぜひぜひチェックしていただければなと思います。
So please be sure to check that out too.
そして、本日のハッシュタグはこちら！
And here is today's hashtag!
ハッシュタグ『百鬼あやめ7周年新衣装3D』で。
Hashtag '#NakiriAyame7thAnniversaryNewOutfit3D'.
ちょっとね、長いんですけど、長いんですけど、
It's a bit long, I know, it's long, but...
このたくさんきれいなこのステージと、余のきれいな衣装をたくさんたくさんスクショして、
...please take lots of screenshots of this beautiful stage and my lovely outfit...
え、一緒にポストしてください！
...and post them together!
はい。ということで今回は、7周年を兼ねた... 7周年！
Right. So this time, celebrating the 7th anniversary... 7th anniversary!
ってことは、余、7年やってるんですか！？っていう感じなんですけど。
Does that mean I've been doing this for 7 years!? That's how it feels.
今回は、その7周年と新衣装お披露目を兼ねたライブとなっております。
This live stream is to celebrate both the 7th anniversary and the new outfit reveal.
これからね、ゲストもたくさん呼んでいますので、楽しみにしててくださーい！
We have many guests coming up, so please look forward to it!
なんと！なんと！
And! And!
最後には、特大サプライズもあるので、
There's a huge surprise at the end,
絶対最後まで見逃さないでね！
so don't miss out until the very end!
チャンネルはそのまま、頼むね！
Don't change the channel, please!
夢の中でも
Even in my dreams
花が散ってる
Flowers are falling
ひらひら舞う暗闇に浮かぶ桜
Cherry blossoms floating in the fluttering darkness
水面に落ちたら君は
If they fall on the water's surface, you...
もう一度咲くのかな
...I wonder if you'll bloom once more
ひらひら ひらら
Hira Hira Hirara
桜月夜に宿る
Dwelling in the moonlit cherry blossom night
いたずらな風 匂いだけ残して
A mischievous breeze, leaving only its scent behind
あぁ 騒ぎ出した
Ah, it's started to bustle
記憶浮かび 沈んでゆく
Memories float up and sink away
沈んでゆく
Sinking away...
思い出の破片 剥がれても
Even if the fragments of memories peel off
光る鱗で隠すの
I hide them with shining scales
眩いほどに 美しい
Dazzlingly beautiful
ひらひらひらら ひらひらひらら
Fluttering, fluttering...
瞼の裏 暗闇に浮かぶ桜
Cherry blossoms floating in the darkness behind my eyelids
水面に落ちたら 君は
Once they fall onto the water's surface, you...
もう一度咲くのかな
Will you bloom once more?
サヨナラしたら 会えないのでしょうか
If we say goodbye, will we never meet again?
言えないままの気持ちだけが
Let only the feelings left unsaid...
花びら浮かんだ 桜の橋になれ
Become a bridge of cherry blossoms with floating petals
当たり前の景色が
The ordinary scenery...
ひらひらと舞い 音もなく消えてく
Flutters and dances, disappearing without a sound
細い雨に 濡れた想いが
Feelings drenched in the fine rain...
霞んでゆく
Are becoming hazy
他の誰かに向けた笑顔に
At the smile directed towards someone else...
忘れた日々も蘇る
Forgotten days also return
色のない夜を 染めてゆく
Coloring the colorless night
君と出会った 去年の春と
Last year's spring when I met you...
同じ場所で同じ景色見つめてた
I was staring at the same scenery in the same place
咲き誇るほどに 痛む
It hurts as much as they bloom in full glory
君がいない桜
The cherry blossoms without you
生まれ変わって また咲くのでしょうか
Will they be reborn and bloom again?
戻れない場所と知りながら
While knowing it's a place I can't return to
散り行く花びら 手のひらにのせて
Placing the falling petals on my palm
花明かりに 誘われて
Enticed by the glow of the blossoms
胸の中に降り積もる
They pile up inside my chest
光と影 舞い散る吹雪の
A fluttering blizzard of light and shadow
思い出だけ白く染めてゆく
Dyeing only the memories in white
ひらひらひらら ひらひらひらら
Fluttering, fluttering...
瞼の裏 暗闇に浮かぶ桜
Cherry blossoms floating in the darkness behind my eyelids
水面に落ちたら 君は
Once they fall onto the water's surface, you...
もう一度咲くのかな
Will you bloom once more?
サヨナラしたら 会えないのでしょうか
If we say goodbye, will we never meet again?
言えないままの気持ちだけが 花びらに変わっても
Even if only the feelings left unsaid turn into petals
君と出会った 去年の春と
Last year's spring when I met you...
同じ場所で同じ景色見つめてた
I was staring at the same scenery in the same place
咲き誇るほどに 痛む
It hurts as much as they bloom in full glory
君がいない桜
The cherry blossoms without you
夢の中でも 花が散ってゆく
Even in my dreams, the flowers are scattering
暗闇に浮かんだ桜が 水面に落ちたら また会えるのかな
If the cherry blossoms in the dark fall on the water, will we meet again?
極楽浄土
Gokuraku Jodo
作詞：MARiA 作曲：toku
Lyrics: MARiA Composition: toku
月明かり昇る刻
When the moonlight rises
灯る赤提灯
The red lanterns are lit
祭囃子の合図
The signal of festival music
ふわり 蝶が 誘い出す
A butterfly gently lures you out
ちょいと覗いて見てごらん
Take a little peek
迷い込めば抜け出せない
Once you wander in, you can't get out
楽しいことがしたいなら
If you want to have some fun
おいであそばせ極楽浄土
Welcome to Gokuraku Jodo
歌えや歌え 心のままに
Sing and sing, just as your heart desires
アナタの声をさあ聞かせて
Now, let me hear your voice
踊れや踊れ 時を忘れ
Dance and dance, forgetting about time
今宵 共に あ狂い咲き
Tonight, let's bloom wildly together
美しく咲く花も
Even the flowers that bloom beautifully
いつか散りゆくもの
Are destined to scatter one day
それならこの一夜を
In that case, let's take this one night
もっと熱く愛したい
And love even more passionately
ちょいと「いいこと」いたしましょう
Let's do something "good" together
これは夢か幻か
Is this a dream or an illusion?
嘘も真も無い世界
A world where neither lies nor truth exist
ゆきましょう極楽浄土
Let's go to Gokuraku Jodo
歌えや歌え 心のままに
Sing and sing, just as your heart desires
乱れる髪も気にせずに
Without even caring about disheveled hair
踊れや踊れ 時を忘れ
Dance and dance, forgetting about time
今宵 共に あ狂い咲き
Tonight, let's bloom wildly together
どいつもこいつもなんだかやっぱノーてんき
Everyone's just so carefree after all
気になるアンタの悩みもきっとしてあるでしょ
I'm sure you have some worries too
ざっとでハンパな憂鬱ももう群れおなじ
Rough and half-baked depressions are all the same
アンタの頭の中はグチャグチャさ
Inside your head is a total mess
ドンマイ兵がいじけないもーていしき
Don't mind, soldiers, don't get discouraged, it's a net-consciousness
いけないいけない事柄なんてないから
Because there's no such thing as 'bad' things
イーアルサンスーじゃんけんぽんでさあおゆき
One, two, three, rock-paper-scissors, now go
ウーリュウチーパで天に召されてく
Five, six, seven, eight, being summoned to heaven
キミは
You are...
もうハイスピードだ
...already at high speed
ありゃま こりゃま お待ちかね
My oh my, here we go, what you've been waiting for
ハチャメチャなドラマ
A chaotic drama
派手にドラが鳴るよ
The gong rings out loudly
い・い・の？づっきゅん
Is it okay? Heart-thump
I Love You なのな
It's 'I Love You', you know
四六時中 愛を頂戴
Give me love 24/7
はて？
Huh?
い・い・っ！？ずばっきゅん
It's okay!? Boom-thump
あ・い・あ・い・もうらぶちゅう
Lovey-dovey, already in love
1/2 じゃもの足りない
1/2 is not enough
避けても結局見えない あいつの胸の内
Even if I avoid it, I can't see into his heart
おませな背伸びも気取りも いらないんだから
I don't need any precocious acting out or pretentiousness
先輩後輩ヤンキーちゃんきー 関係ない
Senior, junior, yankee, chunky, it doesn't matter
いざ尋常に勝負
Now, let's fight fairly
君ともしも その気なら
If you're up for it
ボンデージが始まりそうならさ
If bondage is about to start
また
Yet
居食う技 繰り出す
Unleashing eating skills
僕らってば So Sweet だな
We're so sweet
アレはどこが同じだね
Where is that the same?
ぺちゃくちゃで
Chattering
修羅場
A scene of carnage
鐘が鳴るよ
The bell rings
意味深な like you
Meaningful "like you"
曖昧な愛より三球
Better than vague love, three balls
しのこの言わず さあしてちょうだい
Stop complaining and do it already
待って 一位な天中！
Wait, first place in the heavens!
鼻血ブーなのだ
Nosebleed, boo!
自分の意思は どんなもんじゃい
What's your own will like?
い・い・いいなずきゅん
I-I-Iinazukkyun
I love you なのだ
It's "I love you"
四六時中愛をちょうだい
Give me love all the time
待って 1GPなバッキュン
Wait, 1GP bang
あい、あい、あいはバッキュン
Love, love, love is a bang
1/2（にぶんのいち）がたまんない
1/2 is unbearable
惚れなんて試練 会いたいかも知れん
Falling in love is a trial, I might want to meet
毎晩 競り合い たりないや
Every night competing, it's not enough
風前絶後 天真爛漫
Unprecedented, innocent and cheerful
平愛無常 明鏡止水
Ordinary love is impermanent, clear and serene
NAKIRI AYAME
せーの！ いーち、にっ、さん、はい！
Ready, set! One, two, three, go!
これよりご覧いただきますのは
What you are about to see
私たちの 栄枯盛衰
Is our rise and fall
時代は常に日進月歩
Times are always progressing
追いていけ 老若男女
Follow along, young and old
一見は 勧善懲悪
At first glance, it's moralistic
悪者共を 一刀両断
Cutting down the villains in one stroke
でもホントに それだけで楽しいの？
But is that really all that's fun?
もうなんだって 蒟蒻問答
Oh, whatever, it's all nonsense
どこからともなく現れて
Appearing out of nowhere
すぐにどこかへ 神出鬼没
Off to somewhere else, elusive
チャンスを待ったら一日千秋
Longing for a day waiting for a chance
追いかければ 東奔西走
Running east and west if you chase
時代は常に千変万化
Times are always changing
人の心は 複雑怪奇
Human hearts are complex and mysterious
迷い一つなく 踊りだす
Start dancing without a single doubt
もうどうにも 満身創痍
Already covered in wounds
あぁ 巡り巡って 夜の街
Ah, round and round, through the night city
君は合図出し 踊りだす
You give the signal and start dancing
はぁ〜
Haa~
回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Like scattering petals brilliantly
回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin
髪も振り乱して
With your hair flying wildly
一晩中
All night long
今日と 明日と 明後日と
Today, tomorrow, and the day after
この宴は続く
This feast continues
踊れ 歌え
Dance, sing
一心不乱に 回レ！
Spin with all your heart!
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is the Snow, Moon, and Flowers
この世に平穏 訪れるの
Peace visiting this world
望むべくもなし 丁々発止
No hope for it, clashing swords
猛者共 千客万来
The strong gather, many guests
犇めき合う 群雄割拠
Jostling together, rival chiefs
乗り出すか 一攫千金
Going for it, a windfall
気が付いたら 絶体絶命
Before you know it, you're in a desperate situation
でも本ねのところ どう思ってんの？
But what do you really think deep down?
もうまさしく 奇想天外
Exactly fantastic and bizarre
あぁ 辿り辿って 夜の街
Ah, following and following, through the night city
迷い一つなく 踊りだす
Start dancing without a single doubt
はぁ〜
Haa~
回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Like scattering petals brilliantly
回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin
髪も振り乱して
With your hair flying wildly
一晩中
All night long
今日と 明日と 明後日と
Today, tomorrow, and the day after
この宴は続く
This feast continues
踊れ 歌え
Dance, sing
一心不乱に 回レ！
Spin with all your heart!
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is the Snow, Moon, and Flowers
はぁ〜
Haa~
花で一つ
One with a flower
鳥で二つ
Two with a bird
花で一つ、
One for the flower,
鳥で二つ、
Two for the bird,
手打ち鳴らす
Clapping hands
風で三つ、
Three for the wind,
嗚呼、月出て四つ
Ah, four for the moon rising
鳴らす鳴らす
Ringing, ringing
花で一つ、
One for the flower,
鳥で二つ、
Two for the bird,
手打ち鳴らす
Clapping hands
風で三つ、
Three for the wind,
嗚呼、月出て四つ
Ah, four for the moon rising
鳴らす鳴らす
Ringing, ringing
今は
Right now
回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin
華麗に花弁散らすように
Like petals scattering magnificently
回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ 回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin
髪も振り乱して
With hair disheveled too
一唱、
One chant,
二唱、
Two chants,
今日と、明日と、明後日と
Today, tomorrow, and the day after
この宴は続く
This banquet continues
踊レ、歌エ、
Dance, sing,
一心不乱に回レ！
Spin with single-minded devotion!
今宵は何曜日？
What day of the week is it tonight?
水木金？
Wed, Thu, Fri?
土日月火？
Sat, Sun, Mon, Tue?
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハイヤ
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha-iya
ハッハッハッハッ
Ha ha ha ha
いよーっ！
Iyo-!
ぽん！
Pon!
らっしゃいな平は成り　時が来たざらし
Welcome, peace is made, the time has come
夢うつつ夜もすがら
Half-asleep, all through the night
変わりゆくことに　恐れなしのっぴき
No fear of changing things, no escape
ならぬのは御免
I apologize for what cannot be
手毬唄歌い　君達が誘う
Singing a handball song, you all invite me
やな中に行き後ろ髪を引かれても
Even if I'm pulled back while going into the unpleasantness
進むべきなり
I must move forward
流行り廃りの　浮き世なら
If it's a fleeting world of fashion and fad
嗚呼信ずる者はただ
Ah, the only thing to believe in is
君だけと
Just you
酔い痴れや飲み明かや
Get drunk, drink the night away
案ずることなどないなこの世
There's nothing to worry about in this world
人の世は恨めしい　世情はちゃらちゃら
The human world is spiteful, social conditions are fickle
悲し過ごして混じりそい　それそれそれそれ
Spending time in sadness, mixing in, sore sore sore sore
今を嘆いて昔を愛でても
Even if you lament the present and cherish the past
君の心の内の涙川
The river of tears inside your heart
それじゃ適わん　何処へも
That won't do, nowhere
目眩く舞台に君を連れて
Taking you to the dazzling stage
あまうてなどか　愛しき
Something like rain? My beloved
身勝手なのが世の理か
Is selfishness the way of the world?
万人待つの理想　刻まないど
The ideal everyone waits for, don't carve it
刹那的なのは徒爾ら
Being momentary is in vain
僕ら巡り逢うこと　まさに一期一会
Our meeting is truly a once-in-a-lifetime encounter
酸いも甘いも知れん　連れ添ってこの手握って
Not knowing sour or sweet, staying together, hold this hand
生き辛いとこ　浮き世から
From this fleeting world, where it's hard to live
旗を掲げよ
Raise the flag
宵闇が明く
The twilight breaks
酔い上がりや寝れば忘らる
Once the drunkenness wears off or if I sleep, I'll forget
昔も今も変わらず浮き世
The fleeting world remains unchanged, past or present
人の世は愛おしい　いつだってちゃらちゃら
The human world is precious, always fickle
可笑しがんで笑って愛でて　それそれそれそれ
Finding it funny, laughing, and cherishing it, sore sore sore sore
暮れゆく春も凍てつく雪の日も
Waning spring or freezing snowy days
日出る全ての瞬きを君と見よう
Let's watch every sunrise and every blink together
彩ろ色　何処までも
Colors and hues, to the ends of the earth
常ならぬ見晴らしを眺めて
Gazing at an extraordinary view
開けて花一匁
Open up, Hana Ichimonme
欲しがる欲しがる欲しがる声
The voices wanting, wanting, wanting
勝って選んであっけないって
Winning, choosing, and saying it's disappointing
猿真似の南無三　満ち足りないないない
Monkey-mimicry Namusan, not satisfied at all
未だ進む道半ば
Still in the middle of the journey
如何なる時も歩を前へ出せ
No matter what, take a step forward
流行り廃りの　浮き世なら
If it's a fleeting world of fashion and fad
嗚呼信ずる者はただ
Ah, the only thing to believe in is
君だけと
Just you
酔い痴れや飲み明かや
Get drunk, drink the night away
案ずることなどないなこの世
There's nothing to worry about in this world
人の世は恨めしい　世情はちゃらちゃら
The human world is spiteful, social conditions are fickle
悲し過ごして混じりそい　それそれそれそれ
Spending time in sadness, mixing in, sore sore sore sore
今を嘆いて昔を愛でても
Even if you lament the present and cherish the past
君の心の内の涙川
The river of tears inside your heart
それじゃ適わん　何処へも
That won't do, nowhere
めぐるめくる タイムバイヨイヨイ
Going round and round, time by yoi-yoi
君を連れて
Taking you with me
あまうてなどか 心悲しき
Why do the raindrops feel so sad in my heart?
身勝手なのが 世の理か
Is being selfish just the way of the world?
移ろはばこそ こころなどどを
Because things change, there's nothing to fear
恐るることなど あらざらむ
about things like the heart
ニッポン笑顔百景
Japan: A Hundred Views of Smiles
作詞・作曲・編曲：前山田健一
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: Kenichi Maeyamada
よ〜っ！
Yo~!
じゅげむ じゅげむ 五劫のすりきれ
Jugemu, Jugemu, the wear and tear of five eons
かいじゃりすいぎょの すいぎょうまつ
Gravel and sea-fish, the end of Suigyo
うんらいまつ ふうらいまつ くうねるところに すむところ
Unraimatsu, Furaimatsu, where one eats, sleeps, and lives
やぶらこうじのぶらこうじ
Yaburakoji, Burakoji
ぱいぽぱいぽ ぱいぽのしゅーりんがん
Paipo, Paipo, the Shuringan of Paipo
しゅーりんがんの ぐーりんだい
The Gurindai of Shuringan
しゅーりんがんの ぐーりんだい ぐーりんだいの
The Gurindai of Shuringan, the Gurindai's
ぽんぽこぴーの ぽんぽこなーの ちょうきゅうめいの
Ponpokopi, Ponpokona, the long-lived
ちょうすけ！
Chosuke!
ちょいとお時間いただきます
Please give us a moment of your time
ご清聴ください
Please listen carefully
整いました！
I've got it!
「笑うこと」とかけまして
Comparing 'laughter' to...
「お祭り野郎」と解きます
a 'festival-loving guy'...
そのこころは？ そのこころは？
And the reason is? The reason is?
どちらもハッピ（法被）になるでしょう
Both will become 'happy' (wearing a happi coat)
おあとがよろしいようで
That's it for this bit
わらおう わらおう さあわらいましょ
Let's laugh, let's laugh, come on, let's laugh
こんな時代こそ わらいましょ
Especially in times like these, let's laugh
わらおう ないたら負けだ
Let's laugh, if you cry you lose
やけくそわらいましょ
Let's laugh desperately
波乱万丈 すいもあまいも
Full of ups and downs, both bitter and sweet
乗り越えたあっぱれ 日本人
Bravo to the Japanese who overcame it all
わらおう どんな時でも
Let's laugh, no matter when
なにくそわらいましょ
Let's laugh through everything
わっはっは にょっほっほ
Wah-ha-ha, Nyoh-ho-ho
空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
Don't worry about the mood, just laugh
笑顔！ 笑顔！
Smiles! Smiles!
笑う門には福来たる！
Fortune comes to those who smile!
え〜、皆様、今日はようこそおいでいただきました
Well, everyone, thank you for coming today
ここで一席！！
And now, a short story!
ねずみの娘がお嫁に行って、
A mouse's daughter got married,
じきに帰ってきたんでねずみのおかあさんが大変怒って、
but returned home soon after, making her mother very angry,
「あんな、いいところへ、おまえ嫁いで、
“You were married into such a fine place,
誰が嫌で出てきたんだい？」
who did you dislike so much that you left?”
「いいえ、だーれも嫌じゃないんですけれど、
“No, I didn't dislike anyone,
ご隠居さんがやさしいんで、嫌なの。」
but the retired master was too kind, so I hated it.”
「優しいんなら結構じゃないかぁねぇ。」
“If he was kind, isn't that wonderful?”
「でも、猫なで声ですもの。」
“But, he spoke with a cat-caressing voice.”
忙しさに身を任せて
Surrendering myself to the busyness
消えていくだなんて
To think it would just fade away
べらんめえ！
Don't be ridiculous!
わらおう わらおう 笑えなくても
Let's laugh, let's laugh, even if you can't laugh
笑うしかないでしょ 笑いましょ
All we can do is laugh, so let's laugh
口角上げて ひたすら笑いましょ
Lift the corners of your mouth and just laugh
鬼の乱、大飢饉さえ
Even Oni rebellions and great famines
クリアして現代 日本人
The modern Japanese have cleared them all
わらおう 未来永劫
Let's laugh for all eternity
ぐははと笑いましょ
Let's laugh with a big 'Guhaha'
小娘の戯言と切り捨てないで
Don't dismiss it as just a little girl's nonsense
しかめっつらなんか変な顔 笑顔を見たいから
A scowl is a strange face, I want to see your smile
わらおう わらおう さあわらいましょ
Let's laugh, let's laugh, come on, let's laugh
こんな時代こそ わらいましょ
Especially in times like these, let's laugh
わらおう ないたら負けだ
Let's laugh, if you cry you lose
やけくそわらいましょ
Let's laugh desperately
波乱万丈 すいもあまいも
Full of ups and downs, both bitter and sweet
乗り越えたあっぱれ 日本人
Bravo to the Japanese who overcame it all
わらおう どんな時でも
Let's laugh, no matter when
なにくそわらいましょ
Let's laugh through everything
ひたすら笑いましょ
Let's just keep on laughing
わっはっは にょっほっほ
Wah-ha-ha, Nyoh-ho-ho
空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ
Don't worry about the mood, just laugh
笑顔！ 笑顔！
Smiles! Smiles!
笑う門には福来たる！
Fortune comes to those who smile!
徒花ネクロマンシー
Adabana Necromancy
死んでも夢を叶えたい
Even after death, I want to fulfill my dreams
いいえ、死んでも夢は叶えられる
No, dreams can be fulfilled even after death
それは絶望、それとも希望？
Is that despair, or is it hope?
過酷な運命乗り越えて
Overcome a cruel fate
脈がなくても突き進む
Push forward even without a pulse
それが私たちの佐賀だから！
Because that's our Saga!
誰が弔う
Who will mourn?
死地は彼方
The place of death is far off
静寂を破り
Breaking the silence
芽吹いた夢を
The dreams that have sprouted
穿て
Pierce through
重なる屍
Piling up corpses
高みへ
To the heights
届くまで
Until it reaches
唸れ
Roar
徒花
Barren flower
朽ち果てても進め
Advance even if you rot away
奪わせはしない
I won't let it be taken
尊厳の愚弄に
Against the mockery of dignity
飢餓を解き放て
Release the hunger
枯れても走る
Run even when withered
ことを命と呼べ
Call that 'life'
空に叫ぶ
Scream to the sky
脱・生存の定義
The definition of post-survival
骨を切らせて闇を断て
Let them cut your bone to sever the darkness
雲間に光る
Shining between the clouds
簒奪の勝機
The chance for usurpation
覚悟を
Thrust your resolve
宿命に突きつけて
Into your fate
天下に狂い咲く
Blooming wildly across the world
SAGA
傷ひとつ無い
Without a single wound
手など愚か
Hands are foolish
意思も自由も
Your will and freedom
その身を投げて
Throwing your body away
守れ
Protect it
退くな
Don't back down
涙も血も無い
Without tears or blood
神話を
Until you build
築くまで
A myth
燃えろ
Burn
修羅花
Shura-flower
鼓動亡き世界で
In a world without heartbeats
摂理に抗い
Resist providence
天命も無礼
Defy destiny
切り抜けて
And cut through
心を無くす
Know that losing your heart
ことが死と知れ
Is death
極めど儚い
Fleeting child
傀儡の寵児
Of puppets
目を剥き
Open your eyes wide
牙を剥け
And bare your fangs
いつか誰もが
Someday everyone
散華する捨て石
Will be a sacrificial stone
輝け
Shine
刹那無限の火花
Sparks of eternal moments
乱世に逆上る
Defying the turbulent times
SAGA
何が神の如くか
What is 'God-like'?
裁きなどさせない
I won't let you judge me
希望高らかに
Loudly strike
打ち鳴らせ
The bell of hope
呼吸よりも生きた証
The proof of life more than breath
唸れ
Roar
徒花
Barren flower
朽ち果てても進め
Advance even if you rot away
奪わせはしない
I won't let it be taken
尊厳の愚弄に
Against the mockery of dignity
飢餓を解き放て
Release the hunger
枯れても走る
Run even when withered
ことを命と呼べ
Call that 'life'
空に叫ぶ
Scream to the sky
脱・生存の定義
The definition of post-survival
骨を切らせて闇を断て
Let them cut your bone to sever the darkness
雲間に光る
Shining between the clouds
簒奪の勝機
The chance for usurpation
覚悟を
Thrust your resolve
宿命に突きつけて
Into your fate
荒野を駆ける
Running through the wilderness
乱世に挑む
Challenging the turbulent times
天下に狂い咲く
Blooming wildly across the world
サガ
SAGA
寄り添う二人に 君がオーバーラップ
In the two huddling together, you overlap
色なき風に 思い馳せて
Thinking of you in the colorless wind
触れた手の 温もり今も...
The warmth of your hand I touched, even now...
Stop 時間を止めて
Stop, let time stand still
そういつの日だって
Yes, no matter the day
君の言葉 忘れないの
I won't forget your words
会いたい時に会えない 会いたい時に会えない
When I want to see you, I can't; when I want to see you, I can't
切なくて もどかしい
It's painful and frustrating
から紅に染まる渡月橋
Togetsu Bridge dyed in deep crimson
導かれる日 願って
Wishing for the day I'm guided there
川の流れに 祈りを込めて
Pouring my prayers into the river's flow
I've been thinking about you, I've been thinking about you
いつも こころ 君のそば
My heart is always by your side
いにしえの景色 変わりなく
The ancient scenery remains unchanged
今この瞳に 映し出す
Now reflected in these eyes
彩りゆく 季節越え
Passing through the colorful seasons
Stop 覚えていますか？
Stop, do you remember?
ねぇいつになったら
Tell me, when will it be?
また巡り会えるのかな
That we'll be able to meet again?
会いたい時に会えない 会いたい時に会えない
When I want to see you, I can't; when I want to see you, I can't
この胸を 焦がすの
It burns in my heart
から紅に水くくるとき
When the water is bound in deep crimson
君との想い つなげて
Connecting my feelings with you
川の流れに 祈りを込めて
Pouring my prayers into the river's flow
I've been thinking about you, I've been thinking about you
いつも 君を探してる
I'm always searching for you
君となら 不安さえ
If I'm with you, even anxiety...
どんな時も 消えてゆくよ
...will disappear anytime
いつの間にか 優しく
Softly, before I knew it,
抱きしめられるのかしら
I wonder if I'll be held?
から紅の紅葉達さえ
Even the deep crimson maple leaves,
熱い思いを 告げては
...will declare their passionate feelings
ゆらり揺れて 歌っています
Swaying gently, they are singing
I've been thinking about you, I've been thinking about you
いつも いつも 君想う
Always, always, I think of you
はい！というわけでここまでどうでしたでしょうか？
Yes! So, how has it been so far?
やー、もう数多くのゲストに出ていただいて、余は本当に嬉しいです。
Wow, I'm so happy to have had so many guests join me.
本当に今回のね、ライブは最初にも言ったんですけど、ちょっと和風な感じでまとめさせていただいたので、
As I said at the beginning, I put this live show together with a bit of a Japanese theme,
曲も、もうほぼほぼ全部和風っぽい感じで、ちょっと雰囲気をね、一つに統一して今回はライブを作らせていただきました。
so almost all the songs have a Japanese feel, and I created the live show by unifying the atmosphere.
そして、みんな気づいたかな？ちょっと歌ってる最中、ちょっと気づきました？これ。お、気づきました？
And did everyone notice? Did you notice while I was singing? This. Oh, did you notice?
新しいマイクなんですよ。すごいでしょ？すごいでしょ？え、見て見て。
It's a new microphone. Amazing, right? Right? Look, look.
このちょっと、この分かりますか？このお腹の柄とちょっとお揃いなんですよ。
Do you see this? It matches the pattern on my stomach.
ほら、えっちょう可愛いでしょう、これ！
Look, isn't this super cute?!
イェーイ、これ新しいマイク、あ、ここもね、飾りも付いてるんですよ
Yay! This is my new mic. Oh, and look, it has decorations too!
この鈴と、この紐もね、付いてて、可愛いでしょう。
These bells and this cord too! Isn't it cute?
ハァーイ、これもお似合いです、やったー！
Yay! This suits me perfectly! I did it!
はい！ということで、今回はですね、まだサプライズが残っております。
Alright! So, for today, we still have some surprises left.
ですが、その前に、ちょっと告知をさせて頂こうかなと思います。
But before that, I'd like to make a few announcements.
それでは、告知ドドン！
Now then, here come the announcements! *Drumroll*!
百鬼あやめ、活動7周年記念グッズ！
Nakiri Ayame 7th Anniversary Commemorative Goods!
百鬼あやめ 活動7周年記念
Nakiri Ayame 7th Anniversary Celebration
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい、ということで、最初はこちら！卓上屏風です！
Alright, first up is this! The Desktop Folding Screen!
めっちゃ可愛いでしょう、すごい！
It's so cute, right? It's amazing!
卓上屏風
Desktop Folding Screen
でしょう、えっと、デスク、デスクに立てて飾れるサイズの屏風となっております。
Right? It's a folding screen sized perfectly to stand on your desk.
こちらはですね、我美蘭先生の描き下ろしの、余の本日の新衣装と同じ...
This one features an illustration by Gabiran-sensei, showing me in my new outfit...
...同じ屏風をね、ちょっと飾ってくださいね、みんな。
...the same one as the background! Everyone, please display it!
はい、可愛いでしょう。このステージも、背景のステージも、ちょっとそれっぽい感じに合わせて頂きました。
Yes, it's cute. This stage and the background stage have been matched to that vibe.
可愛い！続いてはこちら！
Cute! Next up, this!
湯呑となっております！
It's a teacup!
湯呑
Teacup (Yunomi)
こちらはですね、三川あゆむ先生に描き下ろしいただいた、ぽよよに乗ったですね...
This features an illustration by Mikawa Ayumu-sensei, of me riding on Poyoyo...
...今回も、こちらの新衣装で乗った余がミニキャラで描かれた湯呑となっております。
...represented as a mini-character in this new outfit. It's so cute!
可愛いでしょう。こうやって乗ってます。乗ってます。
Isn't it cute? I'm riding it like this. Riding it.
はい、可愛いでしょう。そして、続いてはこちら！
Yes, it's cute. And next is this!
こちら！扇子となっております！
This! It's a folding fan!
扇子
Folding Fan
こちらですね、お気づきになりますか？こちらもそうです！
Notice anything about this? That's right!
新衣装と同じ柄の扇子となっております。
This fan has the same pattern as my new outfit.
ちょっとね、ど真ん中に「余」って入ってるんですけど、こちら、入れるかすごい迷いました。
It has 'Yo' right in the middle. I really debated whether to include that or not.
これ余を入れようかな、え、どうしようかなって、運営さんとちょっと話し合って、こちらになりました。
I was like, 'Should I put "Yo" there? Hmm...' I discussed it with the staff, and this is what we decided on.
ちょっとね、あの、この余の右左で、余のこれかな、この振袖と同じ...
On the right and left sides, it matches... this part of my long sleeves...
...こっちの色とこっちの色で、ちょっと新衣装っぽい感じにさせて頂きました。
...using these colors to give it that 'new outfit' feel.
そして、そして、続いてはこちら！卓上ライトとなっております！
And, and, next up is this! It's a desktop light!
行灯風の卓上ライトで、新衣装にこちらもですね、合わせた和風のデザインとなっております。
A lantern-style light with a Japanese design that matches my new outfit.
卓上ライト
Desktop Light
ぜひね、飾って、あの和風っぽい、風情あるお部屋タイムを過ごして頂きたいな、ということで...
I want you to display it and enjoy some elegant, Japanese-style time in your room...
...ちょっと和風よりのライトにさせて頂きました。可愛いでしょう、これ。
...so we made it quite Japanese-style. Isn't it lovely?
いいよね、めっちゃ考えました、こちら。お勧めです。
It's great, right? I put a lot of thought into this. Highly recommended.
はい、続いてはこちら！こちらですね、お馴染み販売ボイス。
Alright, next up! The usual sales voice.
ボイス
Voice
こちらのタイトルは「新衣装でデート」ということで、内容は新衣装の余と...
The title for this one is 'A Date in a New Outfit.' The content features me in my new outfit...
...水辺で、え、水辺でデートをしている内容となっております。
...on a date by the water. By the water!
メッセージにもね、ちょっと水辺、後ろにね、ありますけども、はい。
There's a bit of a waterfront in the background of the message too. Yes.
はい、そしてそして、フルセットご購入の方は、こちらです！
And finally, for those who purchase the full set, here's this!
数量限定バージョンは、直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入り、我美蘭先生描き下ろしのポストカードとなっております！
The limited edition comes with a handwritten signature and a foil-stamped message on a postcard illustrated by Gabiran-sensei!
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
可愛い！通常バージョンはですね、箔押し複製サインとメッセージ入りの...
So cute! The standard version includes a foil-stamped signature and message...
...我美蘭先生描き下ろしポストカードとなっております。
...on the postcard illustrated by Gabiran-sensei.
さらに！新衣装リスナーに褒めてもらって喜んでいる余の特典ボイスがついてきますね、はい。
Plus! It comes with a bonus voice of me getting all happy after being praised for my new outfit!
タイトル「またデートしようね」という、これは一体なんなんだという感じなんですけど、
The title is 'Let's Go on Another Date.' I wonder what that's all about...?
まあね、あの気になる方はぜひ、聞いていただければと思います。
Well, if you're curious, please do give it a listen.
まあ恥ずかしいので、ここら辺にしときます。
It's embarrassing, so I'll stop there.
はい、ということで、以上、百鬼あやめ活動7周年記念グッズでした！
Alright! So that concludes the Nakiri Ayame 7th Anniversary Commemorative Goods!
みんな買ってね、よろしくお願いします。
Please buy them! Thank you for your support.
ということなんですけど、こちら！まだ終わってません！
But that's not all! We're not finished yet!
まだ、チャンネルはそのままで、頼む！ということで、
Stay tuned to the channel! Please!
まあ最初ちょっと言った、そろそろ、まあサプライズを...
Like I mentioned at the start, it's about time for... the surprise.
...みんな気になってると思うんで、ちょっとサプライズに行っちゃおうかなと思います。
I know everyone's curious, so let's get to the surprise!
みんな気になるよね？気になる、気になる。あー、そうですよね。
You're all curious, right? So curious, so curious! Ah, I thought so!
と、その前に、このステージ、上へ参ります！
But before that, this stage is going up!
グングングングン。うわー、上上がってる！
*Rising sound* Whoa, it's going up!
みんな見て、すごいでしょ？見えてる？みんな見て、ステージも、夜も見て！
Everyone look! Amazing, right? Can you see it? Everyone, look at the stage and the night view too!
さて、こちら上に上がってきたんですけれども
Now, I've come up here to the top stage...
まあ上でね、何がやるのかと
Well, you might be wondering what I'm doing up here.
まあ薄々ちょっと気付いてるんじゃないかなとは、まあ思うんですけれども
I think you might have a vague idea already, though.
何かわかるかな？
Do you know what it is?
みんな、教えて教えて教えて
Everyone, tell me, tell me, tell me!
みんな、なんだと思う？なんだと思う？
Everyone, what do you think it is? What do you think?
おもち、ほら、私、おー、遊んでますね、あー
Omochi... look, I'm... oh, you're playing around, huh?
なんと、はい、こちら、なんとこちらです。どどん！
And so... yes, here... here it is! Ta-da!
新曲『花吹雪』でーす！やったー！
My new song, "Hana Fubuki"! Yay!
いや、もうだいぶ長らくお待たせしたと思うんですけれども
I think I've kept you waiting for quite a long time...
余のオリジナル曲の新しいのはいつだ？みたいなね感じで待っていたかと思うんですけど
I'm sure you've been waiting, wondering when my next original song would come out.
えー、こちら、えー、作詞作曲、ベルさんに書いていただけました。
Um, this one... Vell-san wrote the lyrics and composed the music.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much!
テーマはですね、『可憐な歌声 ✕ 和風ロック』。
The theme is "Lovely Singing Voice ✕ Japanese-style Rock".
可愛いだけじゃない一味違うオリジナルソングとなっております。
It's an original song that's a bit different, not just cute.
はい、このね、こう綺麗な可憐で、こう重厚な和風ロックとなっておりますので
Yes, it's a beautiful, lovely, yet heavy Japanese-style rock song...
メロディーとかね歌詞もこだわり抜いて、磨き上げていただいた楽曲となっておりますので
The melody and lyrics were carefully crafted and polished for this track...
ぜひぜひ皆さん、えー聞いてください。
So please, everyone, give it a listen.
9月4日、0時から、本日の0時からですね、各週、音楽サイトでリリースされるのでぜひ聞いてください。
It'll be released on music sites starting at midnight on Sept 4th—tonight—so please listen to it!
聞いてね、いっぱい聞いてね。
Listen to it, okay? Listen to it a lot!
はい、それでは皆さん、大変長らくお待たせいたしました。
All right then, everyone, thank you for waiting so long.
最後はこの新曲『花吹雪』で、えー送らせていただきたいと思います。
For the final song, I'd like to perform this new one, "Hana Fubuki".
感想などもね、この衣装もステージと一緒にポストしてください。
Please post your thoughts about the outfit and the stage as well.
たくさんポストしてね。
Post lots of them, okay?
最後にはですね、メン限パートで、えーちょっと衣装のお写真になったり詳しい感じのお話もしたり
After this, in the member-only part, I'll take some photos of the outfit and talk about it in detail...
ミニライブもありますので、そちらの方もぜひぜひ見に来てくれたら嬉しいです。
...and there will be a mini-live, so I'd be happy if you'd come watch that too!
はい、それでは聞いてください。『花吹雪』
All right, then, please listen: "Hana Fubuki".
共に散る 宿命（さだめ）なら
If it is our fate to scatter together
派手に散りましょう
Let us scatter brilliantly
花吹雪
Hana Fubuki (Flower Storm)
ひらひら舞い落ちる空
Fluttering down from the sky
とうに散った泡沫（うたかた）の夢
A fleeting dream that has long since scattered
千の花は 麗しく咲く
A thousand flowers bloom beautifully
叶う逢瀬（おうせ）は刹那
Our meeting is but a fleeting moment
艶（あで）やかに舞い
Dancing glamourously
蝶の儚き命
The fleeting life of a butterfly
するり堕（お）ちる 今宵は何処（いずこ）
Slipping and falling, where are we tonight?
天の風 揺れる
The winds of heaven sway
狂おしく今咲き誇れ
Bloom in full glory now, as if mad
共に散る 宿命（さだめ）なら
If it is our fate to scatter together
光満ちた舞台で笑え
Smile on this stage filled with light
闇を裂く旋律（メロディ）は
The melody that tears through the darkness
ゆらりと薫る
Wafts gently
夢を咲かせましょう
Let us make our dreams bloom
花吹雪
Hana Fubuki
くらくら燃ゆるは焔（ほむら）
Dizzying and burning is the flame
遠く咲いた 明日の夢
The dream of tomorrow that bloomed far away
正か否か 惑わずにゆこう
Right or wrong, let's go without hesitation
過去の痛みを胸に
Keeping past pains in our hearts
誰（た）そ彼（かれ）に
At twilight
祈りをひとつ
A single prayer
涙の川を
The river of tears
穿（うが）つ声 響く
A voice that pierces resonates
慎ましくただ進むだけ
Just moving forward modestly
茜（あかね）さす 空の果て
At the edge of the madder-red sky
褪（あ）せた過去の憧れを見る
Seeing the faded longings of the past
澄み渡る 静寂に
In the clear silence
未来を繋ぐ
Connecting to the future
答え求（もと）めれど 術（すべ）無し
Though I seek an answer, there is no way
共に散る 宿命（さだめ）なら
If it is our fate to scatter together
光満ちた舞台で笑え
Smile on this stage filled with light
闇を裂く旋律はゆらりと薫る
The melody that pierces the darkness wafts gently
夢を咲かせましょう 花吹雪
Let's make our dreams bloom, Hanafubuki
出演：百鬼あやめ、AZKi、兎田ぺこら、フワワ、モココ、大神ミオ
Cast: Nakiri Ayame, AZKi, Usada Pekora, Fuwawa, Mococo, Ookami Mio
白上フブキ、さくらみこ、宝鐘マリン、天音かなた、雪花ラミィ
Shirakami Fubuki, Sakura Miko, Houshou Marine, Amane Kanata, Yukihana Lamy
7周年記念ライブ見てくれてありがとう！新衣装にキレイなステージどうだったかな？
Thank you for watching the 7th anniversary live! How did you like the new outfit and the beautiful stage?
みんなが少しでも笑顔になってくれたら嬉しいです！！8年目もよろしくね！大好き！♡
I'd be happy if this made you smile even just a little!! Look forward to my 8th year too! I love you! ♡